(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T14:26:34.284484",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
君の髪の香り はじけた
The scent of your hair burst forth,
浴衣姿が まぶしすぎて
Your yukata appearance was too dazzling.
お祭りの夜は 胸が騒いだよ
Festival nights make my heart flutter.
はぐれそうな人ごみの中
In the crowd where we might get separated,
「はなれないで」 出しかけた手を
"Don't leave me," I reached out my hand
ポケットに入れて 握りしめていた
And squeezed it tight in my pocket.
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
子供みたいに 金魚すくいに
Like a child, engrossed in scooping goldfish,
夢中になって 袖がぬれてる
With my sleeves all wet.
無邪気な横顔が とても可愛くて
Your innocent profile was so adorable.
君は好きな綿菓子買って
You bought your favorite cotton candy,
ご機嫌だけど少し向こうに
Looking happy, but seeing a friend
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
ハロー！みんな！
Hello everyone!
アイドル以上のロボ子だよ！
It's Roboco, better than an idol!
見てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for watching!
今日はしっかり目に焼き付けてね！
Burn this into your memories today!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
せーの！で！いいよ！
Ready, set, go!
神社の中 石段に座り
Sitting on the shrine's stone steps,
ぼーっとした闇の中で
In the hazy, quiet darkness,
ざわめきが少し遠く聞こえた
The commotion sounded a bit far away.
線香花火 マッチをつけて
Lighting sparklers with a match,
色んな話しだけれど
We talked about various things...
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer with you is a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
Fireworks disappearing into the sky.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
君がいた夏は 遠い夢の中
The summer spent with you was a distant dream,
空に消えてった 打ち上げ花火
fading away into the sky, like fireworks.
はーいロボ子ー！
Hi, Roboco!
ちょっと待って鼻声。
Wait, my nose is stuffy.
はーいロボ子ー！
Hi, Roboco!
よいしょ。みんな聞こえてますかー？
There we go. Can everyone hear me?
たくさの応援ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the support!
パチパチいっぱいありがとうございます。スパチャもいっぱいありがとう！
Thank you for the applause, and thanks for all the Superchats!
というわけでちょっと待って。
So anyway, hold on a second.
お水飲んでもいいかな。
Is it okay if I drink some water?
はーいというわけでロボ子。
So anyway, Roboco...
みんな遊びに来てくれてありがとう！見てますか？
Thanks everyone for coming to hang out! Are you watching?
いや、見えない魔女ちゃんがここにいました。
Oh, the invisible witch-chan was right here.
というわけで、えー、ロボコの3Dアイドルライブに来てくれてみんなありがとう！
Thanks for coming to Roboco's 3D idol live!
早速、いや緊張してた。
Right away—well, I was so nervous.
え、見えてた？見えてた？めちゃめちゃ可愛いよ。
Huh, could you see me? It's super cute.
はーいというわけで、お水もいっぱ飲ませていただきまして、
So having let me drink plenty of water,
一曲目開幕にね、歌わせていただいたのは夏祭りでございます！
the opening song we sang for the first track was "Natsumatsuri"!
なんか今日すごいさ、いろんなところで夏祭りがあるらしいからさ、やべ、ロボ子もやっぱ夏祭りしなきゃなと思って歌いました。
There seem to be summer festivals all over today, so I thought, "Oh, Roboco has to do one too," and sang it.
はい、えーと合わせてて今日もみんなずっと振ってね！ずっと止まってないね！
Yeah, everyone kept waving along today too! You didn't stop at all!
止まらんね！なぁ！そう花火上がってるらしいしね！
You really don't stop! Right?! And fireworks seem to be going up too!
みんな、みんな今日お祭りらしいからね、一発目はロボ子もお祭りいばさせていただきました！
Since everyone's having a festival today, Roboco had her festival for the first song too!
目回る方はね、ぜひサリームをね昨日新規で新品でヒヤストロでぜひぜひいっぱい使っててください！
For those who get dizzy, please definitely use Salim, brand new with Hyastro, a lot!
その方のね肩もねぜひいっぱいいましとこで可愛くやってって盛り上げていきましょう！
And let's make it cute and get hyped up together!
そういや、気づいたみんな？この格好、これ…
Oh yeah, did you guys notice? This outfit, this...
え？ロボ子、豊水衣莉、してないアイドル衣装って？ま！？
Eh? Roboco wearing an idol outfit she hasn't worn at Toyosu? Really?!
はい、こちらあの、あの豊水ライブで歌ったアイドル衣装だよ！凄くない？
Yes, this is the idol outfit I sang in at that Toyosu live! Isn't that amazing?
え、ロボ子ねちょっとお気に入りポイントがねさっき見つけてしまったんだけど、ちょっと…横向いていい？横、横向いていい？
Um, Roboco found a favorite point earlier, but... can I turn sideways? Can I turn sideways?
え？分かる？僕の月のとこ今のバレたかな？
Eh? Can you? Did my moon part just get exposed?
もうちょっとけっこう上の、えっえっな感じなっちゃうんだけど、え,よくさ、すん、え、よくない？ちょっと見えてるかも…
It gets a bit high up like eh-eh, but isn't it good? It might be a little visible...
すごい！すごい！ああ、好きって思って、赤也さんもありがとうね！
Amazing! Amazing! Ah, I thought "I love it," Akaya-san thank you too!
もうすごい！あ、ちらっ
It's so amazing! Ah, peek—
ちらっ、あ、ちらっ、あ、ちらっ、はいっ、ちらっ
Peek, ah, peek, ah, peek, yep, peek!
あそこなんですね。いやどこが好きとは言ってないんですけど、まあそこなんですね。
So it's there. Well, I didn't say which part I liked, but I guess it's there.
でもめちゃめちゃ可愛い、ふりふりふりふりしてるしょ？
But it's super cute, shaking and fluttering like this, right?
そうなんです。こちらね、あの時の豊水のライブが思い出されるね。ふりふり。
That's right. This brings back memories of that Toyosu live. Flutter flutter.
スタンスタンスタンスタン、くるっ！可愛いしょ？可愛いしょ？みんな！
Stun stun stun stun, spin! Cute, right? Cute, right, everyone?
今日ね右手が調子いい、左手ちょっと、これ…こんな感じ。
Today my right hand is in good shape, my left hand is a bit... like this.
ちょっとロボ子の手がね直りきらんかった。
Roboco's hand just didn't fully recover.
ちょっとめっちゃこっちの手でだからめっちゃ挿していこうねって思ってる。
So I'm thinking, "Let's poke out a lot with this hand."
この左右一体感、たまらん。いやマジで可愛いよね、おへそも見えてる。
This sense of unity on both sides is irresistible. Seriously, even my belly button is showing.
今日はいっぱい見せてもいい日。とわぴ！
Today is a day where I can show it off plenty. Towapi!
可愛い、ありがとうとわぴ！
So cute, thank you Towapi!
いやとわぴとはね、いつか横で歌いたいな。すって。
Man, I'd love to sing side by side with Towapi someday.
はい、というわけでね、えーこちら見えるかな？みんな目付いてる？
Alright, so, um, can you guys see this? Is everyone keeping your eyes open?
こちらロボコの3Dアイドルライブ、なんだねこのタグを決めたきっかけは…
This is Roboco's 3D idol live, what was the reason we decided on this tag...
みこちのサムネからなんですけど、そう、めちゃめちゃ可愛いなって思ったんでそのまま…
It started from Miko-chi's thumbnail, yeah, I thought it was super cute, so just like that...
こちら、このタグでぜひいっぱいつぶやいて、スクショや岐阜いっぱい、いっぱい撮ってって！
Please tweet a lot with this tag, and take lots and lots of screenshots and GIFs!
肝臓痛いぞもね？
My liver hurts, too?
しとって下さい、目も付いてるよ？
Please do, my eyes are on, too?
目付いてた？
My eyes were on?
ああ、さすがじゃあ、じゃあいっぱい僕のこと目開けてみてね。
Ah, as expected, so open your eyes wide and look at me.
そう。
Right.
そう、というわけでね、こちらじゃじゃーん！
Anyway, here it is, ta-da!
アミゴチのサムネね、ちゃんと記念になんの後直してくれたんだよ。ごめんねロボ子意地張ってきて。
Amigochi's thumbnail, she fixed it properly later for the commemoration. Sorry, Roboco was being stubborn.
そう、ロボ子すごい迷っちゃったんだよね。戻すべきなのか戻さないべきかで悩んでたんだけど、
Yeah, Roboco was really hesitating. I was wondering whether I should revert it or not.
なんか今日すまるの配信で、ロボ子さん30周年記念って、あれ？なんか、なんか製造みたいになってない？みたいになって、
Like, today during Sumaru's stream, "Roboco-san's 30th-anniversary," huh? Wait, doesn't it look like manufacturing? Like that,
あ、もうやっぱすぐ変えてやろうと思って変えちゃった。
Ah, I thought I should change it right away and changed it.
そうなんです。
That's right.
はい、というわけで、ロボ子の30、30周年記念じゃないよ！違うよ、長い記念よ！違うよ、まだ4歳！
Yeah, so today is Roboco's 30, no, 30th-anniversary! No, wait, long anniversary! No, I'm still 4 years old!
違う、違う違う違う！30周年じゃないよ！ドラえもんみたいになっちゃうよ！違うよ、えっと、なんだっけ？30、30、30万人記念だ！
No, no, no, no! It's not the 30th anniversary! I'll end up like Doraemon! No, wait, what was it? 30, 30, 300,000 subscribers celebration!
はい、というわけで今日は30万人記念なのでね、30万人記念のロボ子の3D全身配信のね、やつとなっております。
Yes, so today is the 300,000 subscribers celebration, so it's Roboco's 3D full-body distribution stream!
はい、あ、どうも、え、ハロー!ホロライブ所属ゼロ期生のバーチャルロボットのロボ子だよ！この間練習したんだ、この文言。
Yes, ah, hello, uh, Hello! Virtual robot Roboco of Hololive 0th generation! I practiced this phrase the other day.
ちゃんと言えた気がす、あ、高精度ロボットもいちゃーもってことだけは忘れないでください。はい。
I feel like I said it right... ah, just don't forget that I'm a high-precision robot YouTuber. Yes.
ねえ、あ、はい、というわけでね、次の曲からもうどんどんね、いっぱいっぱい、いっぱい歌っていこうと思うので、楽しみにして聴いていってください。今日はいろんな歌を歌いたいと思います。
Hey, ah, yes, so from the next song onwards, I'll be singing lots and lots more, so please look forward to listening. Today I'd like to sing various songs.
うん、また超高精度のが。あー。よし。
Yeah, and super high-precision... ah. Alright.
じゃあね、次はちょっと可愛い曲歌います。みんなが可愛いって言ったらどの曲かなって思うんだけど、ちょっとちょっとちっちゃくなって歌おうかなって思います、気持ちがね。
So next, I'll sing a rather cute song. I wonder which song people call cute, so I think I'll sing it feeling a bit smaller, in my mood.
風船。
Balloon.
はい、じゃあそれは聴いてください。確信的メタモルフォーゼ！どうぞ。
Yes, please listen to that. Kakushin-teki Metamaru Fōze! Here we go.
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ! UMAじゃないよ うまる!
U.M.R! Hai! U.M.R! Hai! It's not UMA, it's Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊 遊び倒せ!
Always give your all and play to the max!
もっと もっと 楽しめよ 乙女!
Enjoy it more and more, maidens!
みんなに気づかれないように
So that no one notices you,
いざ、行け! 干物妹ライフ
Now, go! Umaru-chan's dried-up life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Wearing your favorite hoodie,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Lounging around lazily today as well,
大好物のポテチを手ニ
Grabbing your favorite potato chips,
パソコンと睨めっこしよう
Let's have a staring contest with the PC.
立てば芍薬 すわれば牡丹 歩く姿は百合の花
A peony when standing, a lotus when sitting, a lily when walking—
誰もがうらやむ完璧JK
The perfect high school girl everyone envies!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ!
Once you pass the front door, it's transformation time!
さあ宴の始まりだぁ!
Now let the banquet begin!
可憐で優雅な女の子演じてみても
Even if you act like a graceful and cute girl,
お兄ちゃんだけはだませない
You can't fool your big brother alone.
素直に言えない 「ありがとう」 態度でしめそう…
Showing the "Thank you" you can't honestly say through your attitude...
だい! 言陣撤回! ああもういいじゃない!!
Wait! Retract that statement! Oh well, whatever!!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない!!
I don't care about big brother at all!!
なんすっしって!?
What did you say!?
一心同体 ふたりでひとつだってだってそれがきょうだいでしょ?
Body and soul, two in one, after all, that's what siblings are, right?
一蓮托生 ふたりぎりの運命共同体 今日だって
Sharing the same fate, just the two of us bound by destiny, even today!
自由奔放 笑い飛ばせ! もっともっと楽しんだもん勝ち
Laugh off the unbridled freedom! Whoever has the most fun wins!
天真爛漫 スマイルでぎゅっとぎゅっと心をつかみちゃうの やりたい放題は信頼の裏返し?
Innocent and radiant, grabbing your heart tight with a smile. Is doing whatever you want a sign of trust?
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ! UMAじゃないよ うまる!
U.M.R! Hai! U.M.R! Hai! It's not UMA, it's Umaru!
外では猫をかぶり 今日も明日も演じるのです
Wearing a mask outside, acting day after day,
大好評の笑顔を武器に 友達にバレないように
Using your well-received smile as a weapon so friends won't find out.
たとえば二頭身 すわれば満丸 歩く姿はちきちくるん
A two-head-tall chibi when sitting, waddling when walking—
誰でも癒やせる愛嬌マスコット!?
An adorable mascot that heals everyone!?
さあ限界越えるまでパーティナイト! 宴の始まりだぁ!
Now, party night until we break our limits! Let the banquet begin!
お兄ちゃんは どこだろー？
Where is big brother?
みんなは どこなのさー？
Where is everyone?
逃んでゆくこのおんなの声を お兄ちゃんでみても
Even if you listen to this woman's voice calling out,
お兄ちゃんだけは ダメさせない 嫌われたくない も
You can't let just big brother... I don't want to be hated,
素直にいえない ありがとうの態度でしめそう
Showing the "Thank you" I can't honestly say through your attitude...
なぜ限定撤回 さあもういいじゃない!!
Why retract the statement? Oh well, whatever!!
U.M.R! ハイ! U.M.R! ハイ!
U.M.R! Hai! U.M.R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
I'm not a UMA, I'm Umaru!
U.M.R! ハイはい! U.M.R! ハイはい!
U.M.R! Hai hai! U.M.R! Hai hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる!
I'm not a UMA, I'm Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊遊び倒せ
Always give it your all and play to the fullest!
もっともっと楽しめよ乙女
More and more, enjoy yourself, maiden!
みんなに気づかれないように
Make sure nobody notices you,
いざ、ゆけ! 干物妹ライフ
Now, go! Your Himouto life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Putting on your favorite hoodie,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロしてさ
Lazing around today just like any other day,
大好物のポテチを手ニ
With your favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンと睨めっこしよう
Playing a staring contest with the computer.
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
Like a peony when standing, a tree peony when sitting,
歩く姿は百合の花
Walking like a lily flower,
誰もが羨む完璧JK
A flawless high school girl everyone envies.
玄関くぐったら変身だ!
Once you pass through the front door, it's time to transform!
さあゴータラしよう
Come on, let's be lazy!
いつだって "食う! 寝る! 遊ぶ!" の3連コンボ
Always, the triple combo of "Eat! Sleep! Play!"
ずっとずっとゲームは友達
Games are your friends forever and ever,
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけれど
Big brother might be strict,
きっときっと許してくれるの
But surely, surely he'll forgive you,
止めようと思ったのに動いちゃった最後おしまい
I tried to stop, but I ended up moving! That's the end!
止めようおしまい
Let's stop, that's it.
止めようと思ったのに動いちゃったかわいい
I tried to stop, but I moved! So cute.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
動いちゃった 止めるって
I moved! I decided I was
最後止めるんだって決めてさ 動いちゃった
going to stop at the very end, but I moved.
まねちゃんが まねちゃん多分めちゃめちゃ動いてたから 食べてお水持ってきてくれた
Mane-chan probably moved so much that they brought me water.
優しいか
How kind.
はいということでね え、うまるんでございました
So, yeah... um, that was Umaru.
いやみんな乗ってたね
Man, everyone was getting into it.
ありがとう手をパチパチもありがとう
Thank you, thank you for the clapping too!
熱っ
Hot!
めちゃめちゃ熱いよみんな
It's super hot, everyone!
可愛いかったですか?
Was it cute?
好きだ 素敵だ ありがとう
I love it, it's wonderful, thank you!
サンキュー サンキュー
Thank you, thank you!
RBC RBCロボ子ロボ子ロボ子ロボ子
RBC, RBC, Roboco, Roboco, Roboco, Roboco!
そう ちょっと迷ったんだよね
Yeah, I was a bit hesitant.
でも RBCってクソ言いづらくない?ってなってもうまるにしようと思って
But I thought, 'Isn't RBC super awkward to say?', so I decided to go with Umaru.
RBC RBCってめちゃめちゃ早口だねって思ってさ ロボコロボコロボコロボコだったらわかるけど
I thought, 'RBC, RBC is super fast-paced,' though Roboco, Roboco, Roboco, Roboco makes sense.
でもなんかロボ子さ RBCって言う単語を見るとさ 分かるんだけどさ なんか録画されてる気分になるんだよね
But you know, whenever Roboco sees the word RBC, I understand it, but it feels like I'm being recorded.
なんだっけ レックか
What was it, REC?
RECかRECと めっちゃ似てるからさ RBCの列がいっぱいあるとさ
REC, it looks so much like REC, so when there's a bunch of RBC rows,
なんかすごい盗撮されてる気分になるの
it feels like I'm being secretly filmed.
すごい すごい盗撮されてる気分になる赤いなんか丸のさ マークがついてる感じでレックレックって感じ
It feels like I'm being secretly filmed, with a red circle mark and everything, like 'REC, REC'.
めちゃくちゃに可愛かった? 嬉しい ありがとう!
Was it super cute? I'm so happy, thank you!
そうなんかロボ子にしてさ めちゃめちゃはしゃいでると思わない? めちゃめちゃはしゃいだなあって今自分でもびっくりしてる
Yeah, and for Roboco, don't you think I was super hyped? I'm surprised at myself for being so hyped.
疲れ立った 疲れ立った
I'm exhausted, I'm exhausted.
すっごい
Whoa...
足が変な感じするの
My legs feel kind of weird.
ロボ子の足みんな見た?
Did everyone see Roboco's legs?
ロボ子の足 変な感じするの
Roboco's legs feel weird.
なんか いつもの足じゃないのロボ子
It's not Roboco's usual legs.
アイドルがんばって いやなんかホロライブもちょっと座ってもペシャってなってもいいって言われて
Doing my best as an idol... Well, they told me in Hololive it's okay to sit down or get flattened.
そう ほら 靴履いてるのアイドル衣装って
Yeah, look, idol outfits include shoes.
変な感じしない?
Doesn't it feel weird?
なんかロボ子変な感じがすごいんだよね ほら ほら 三つ指が隠されてるの
Roboco feels super weird... Look, look, my three fingers are hidden.
爪貫通してね? マジ?
Did my claws pierce through? Seriously?
待って 見えてじゃ 貫通してないよ 見えてじゃ
Wait, I can see... No, they didn't pierce through. I can see.
なんかさ いつもロボ子見せてるけどさ 入っちゃうとさ ちょっと 見せづらくなっちゃう
Usually Roboco shows them, but once they're in, it gets a bit hard to show.
そう いつも いつも穿いてないのに
Yeah, even though I usually don't wear them.
いつもノーパン うるさいやい! うるさいやい! 今はスカート穿いてるんだい 女の子だよ そう
I usually go no-pa-- Shut up! Shut up! I'm wearing a skirt right now! I'm a girl, yeah.
そう これはね アイドル用の足パーツでございます
Yeah, these are foot parts for idols.
ああ ほぼ人間 いやいや まぁ高性能すぎて見えない ロボットに見えないかな?
Ah, almost human... No, well, they're too high-performance, maybe I don't look like a robot?
いや 隠されてる この もはや これもうね 柄に見えてくる 腕もね
No, they're hidden. At this point, it even starts looking like a pattern on my arms too.
こじつけたらわかるかな
If I force it, will you understand?
髪の毛が長すぎてね、
My hair is so long,
リボンが、
the ribbon...
あ、ほらほら！
Ah, look, look!
おっきいリボンが背中にも付いてるの。
There's a big ribbon on my back too.
髪の毛がふぁーってしないとわかんないや。
If my hair isn't fluffy, you won't notice.
うわぁ！
Whoa!
髪の毛が長すぎて見えねぇ！
My hair is too long, I can't see!
可愛い、こじつけより？
Cute, more than a stretch?
これもっと近づこ慣れんのかな。
Can I get used to getting closer?
おー、ちか！
Whoa, close!
待てや、やだ。
Wait, no way.
やだ、やだ近すぎる。あ、近く来て。
No, no, too close. Ah, come closer.
あ、近く来て。
Ah, come closer.
おー、ちこよりちこより。
Whoa, closer, closer.
おー！
Whoa!
にぱー！
Nipaa!
近すぎてわからんじゃい！
It's too close to tell!
心の底からめちゃめちゃ揺れてる。
My heart is shaking like crazy.
すー、すー、おー！
Su-, su-, whoa!
皆さんここースクショのところでございますよ。
Everyone, this is the screenshot moment right here.
撮れましたか？
Did you capture it?
ちゅーん！
Chuun!
スクショの、スクショのところでございますよ。
It's the screenshot, screenshot moment!
撮れましたか？
Did you capture it?
ちょ！
Whoa!
撮れましたか？
Did you capture it?
そう。髪飾りもめちゃめちゃ可愛いしょ？
Yeah. The hair ornament is super cute, right?
え、可愛い？
Eh, cute?
ちなみに今日のロボ子のマイクは、こちらヘッドホン、
By the way, today's microphone for Roboco is this, headphone,
ヘッドホンのマイクになっております。
headphone microphone.
ここからね、声がめちゃめちゃ通っておりますゆえ。
From here, my voice carries extremely well, so...
鼻息だけあんまり入らないように頑張ってます。
I'm trying hard not to let too much breathing sound in.
うーん、これがアイドル、そう、これがアイドルなんです。
Hmm, this is an idol. Yes, this is an idol.
じゃあ心を落ち着けて、今度はね、少し大人っぽい曲を、
Now, calming my heart, next, a slightly more mature song,
歌っていこうとまいります。
I'm going to sing.
というわけで、えー、大人っぽい曲、ロボ子の思う大人っぽい曲を歌わせていただきます。聞いてください。
So, um, I will sing a mature song, a mature song as Roboco imagines it. Please listen.
神様に恋をしていた頃は
Back when I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never thought such a parting would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again,
せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
at least for the last time, I wanted you to hold me once more.
It's long long good-bye...
さよなら さよなら 何度だって
Goodbye, goodbye, over and over again
自分に 無上に 言い聞かせて
I tell myself endlessly.
手を振るのは優しさだよね?
Waving goodbye is an act of kindness, right?
今強さが欲しい
Now I want strength.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the star shone, and I was born.
愛し続ければ i あればこそ
If we keep loving, if there is love...
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will happen?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkling of planets blurred by tears is gone...
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりも
I won't forget your warmth,
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
nor your kindness, nor the hands that wrapped around me entirely.
It's long long good-bye...
さよなら さよなら 愛しい人
Goodbye, goodbye, my beloved.
貴方が いたから 歩いてこれた
Because you were here, I was able to walk this far.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね?
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now I want an answer.
燃える様な流星 捕まえて
Catching a blazing meteor,
火を灯して
lighting a fire...
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved,
冷えたカラダひとつで
with just a chilled body,
世界は どうなるの?
what will become of the world?
張り続けていた 虚勢が溶けていく
The bravest front I kept up is melting away.
long for...
どうしてなの?
Why is it?
涙溢れて 止められない
Tears overflow and cannot be stopped.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the star shone, and I was born.
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I didn't think such a parting would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I couldn't ever touch you again,
せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
I'd want you to embrace me one last time.
It's long long good-bye...
さよなら さよなら 何回だって自分に無上に言い聞かせて
Goodbye, goodbye, over and over again
手を振るのは優しさだね 今強さが欲しい
Waving my hand is kindness, right? Now, I want strength.
貴方に出逢い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて 愛せばこそ iあればこそ
I met you, stars shone, and I was born; if I love, if there's I...
希望のない奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に浸る 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりも
I can't forget your warmth,
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
and those hands that wrapped me in your kindness.
It's long long good-bye...
さよなら さよなら 愛しい人 貴方がいたから 歩いてこれた
Farewell, my love; I came this far because you were here.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよ
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now I want the answer.
燃えるような流星 捕まえて火を灯して
Catch a falling star and light a fire.
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love and be loved.
冷えたカラダひとつで 世界はどうなるの?
With just a cold body, what becomes of the world?
張り続けてた 虚勢が溶けてく long for...
The facade I kept up is melting away...
どうしてなの? 涙溢れて 止められない
Why? Tears overflow and I can't stop them.
貴方に出逢い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて 愛せばこそ iあればこそ
I met you, stars shone, and I was born; if I love, if there's I...
希望のない奇跡を待って どうなるの? 涙だいに滲む
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
星回り変わって また巡り会えるなら その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
If we are reborn and meet again, find me then.
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえてて
Hold me and never let me go again.
ひとりじゃないと 囁いてほしい planet...
Whisper that I'm not alone, planet...
はい。
Hi.
どうでしたか?
How was it?
ということで、ダイヤモンドクレバースでございました。
And that was "Diamond Crevache."
息つく間もない歌声ですか、本当?
Was it a breathless song? Really?
よかった!
That's great!
聞いてくれてありがとうございました!
Thank you for listening!
やっぱりアイドルなんやなって、
I guess I really am an idol...
やっぱりロボ子もアイドルなんだなってな。
Roboco really is an idol, huh.
聞きすぎとコメントの中でいっぱいちゃんと聞いてくれたんだね。
You listened so well and read lots of the comments.
ありがとう!さっきよーびちゃんもいた気がする、よーびちゃんも来てくれてありがとう!
Thank you! Yobi-chan was here too, thanks for coming!
ねえ。
Right?
今日もでもここまでで分かると、結構いろんなジャンルのやつを歌わせていただいてる気がするやっぱね。
Looking back, I feel like I've sung quite a variety of genres.
30万人記念ね、いろんな歌もねいっぱい歌ってきたからね。
For the 300k milestone, I've sung lots of different songs.
そう、いろんなジャンルがね、好きなジャンルはあるけれども、他のジャンルもいっぱいいっぱい好きだからね、今回はいっぱいいろんな歌を歌わせていただきたいなっていう感じでございます。
So this time I wanted to sing a wide variety of songs.
うん!素晴らしい、よかった!やっぱ高性能なんだな。
Wonderful, I'm glad! I guess I really am high-spec.
なんか地元のポンコツってたまに言われるけど、ロボ子認めたことないからね。
People sometimes call me a local dummy, but I never admit it.
最高すぎてやばい、本当ですか?ありがとうございます!
It's too amazing, is that true? Thank you!
髪の毛が、シュボってなる、ビュルンってなるわ。
My hair goes whoosh!
というわけで、みんなはちなみにどんな声のロボ子が好きですか?どんな歌とか、どんな歌い方をしてるロボ子かな?
So what kind of Roboco voice do you guys like?
ワンチャン次にあるかな?その、その、そのなんか歌い方を次の選曲でやるやつがあるかな?
Maybe there's a song like that in the next lineup?
ふっ、本当？
Huh? Really?
本当、やばい。ポハッてそう。
Seriously, that's crazy. Looks like it'll pop.
ポハッ
Pop!
モンコジナなんてハスキー。
Monkojina is so husky.
ハスキー、ボイス、低い声。ふーん。
Husky voice, low voice. Hmm.
低い声、低い、あ、低い声が、あ、本当か。あ、こ、こ、低い声が好きなんだ。
Low voice, low, oh right, you like low voices.
あ、ふーん。あ、低い声が好き。
Ah, hmm. Ah, I like low voices.
ハローボイ……ハローボイ……
Hello boy... Hello boy...
あ、低い声が好きなんだね。
Ah, so you like low voices, huh?
はーい。はーい。あ、低い声が好きなんだ。なるほどね。
Yes, yes. Ah, you like low voices. I see.
あ、どうもロボ子だよ。低い声も好きなんだ。へえー。
Ah, hello, I'm Roboco. You like low voices too? Huh.
じゃあ、僕が僕の代わりに
Well then, in place of myself...
歌っちゃおうかな。どうよ。
Maybe I'll sing. How's that?
僕が僕の代わりに歌っちゃおうかな。どうよ。
Maybe I'll sing in my place. How's that?
というわけで、次の曲聞いてくれる？
So, will you listen to the next song?
フィクサー。どうぞ。
Fixer. Here you go.
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
Until the day I erase all memories up to today, I cannot sleep
あしたから生きていく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I desperately want a substitute to live my life from tomorrow on
大丈夫と言わせて 後から君のせいにしてはくれないか
Let me say "It's alright," and later, won't you let me blame it on you?
今更意味ないから 後から君のせいにしてはくれないか
It's meaningless now, so later, won't you let me blame it on you?
昨日の足音を 言葉を忘れる
Yesterday's footsteps, forgetting words
一言も一言ばかりに もう奪われるくらい
Just every single word, enough to be stolen away
意味を成さない 何も出来ない
Making no sense, unable to do anything
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らせない
Can't see, want to run, want to fly, want to stop, can't look away
だから 沈め 沈め
Therefore, sink, sink
這い上がれないほどまで
To the point where I cannot crawl back up
飽きるまで 落とせ 落とせ
Until I'm sick of it, drop it, drop it
救い垂らす時まで
Until the time you dangle salvation
嘘臭い粒子の粒を咽喉から絞り出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
I chew up fake particles along with the screams squeezed from my throat
笑顔が下手なばっかりで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Just bad at smiling, playing along with knowing tones to get by
なりたくなかった 今日役に立つ 眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by sleepy, sleepy ideals that are useful today
一番目は「い」の口で言う
The first one is said with an "I" mouth shape
力強く 固く 痛く 噛み締めて
Strongly, firmly, painfully, biting down
死んでしまえ しまえ
Just die, die away
この先も過去も知らず 嫌いなら 壊せ 壊せ
Knowing neither future nor past, if you hate it, break it, break it
どうせなら加害者になればいい
If it's going to be like this, I might as well become the perpetrator
食べきれない棘立ちも 何も生まれない悲しみも
The unfinishable thorns, the sorrow that bears nothing
味気なくて吐き出す前に もう もう次を歌え
Before spitting it out tastelessly, sing the next one already
沈め 沈め
Sink, sink
落とせ 落とせ
Drop it, drop it
救い垂らす時まで
Until the time you dangle salvation
どうせなら踊り踊れ
If it's going to be like this, dance, dance
灰色になり切る前に 打ち鳴らせ
Before turning completely gray, ring it out
変われ 変われ
Change, change
眠り落ちる時まで
Until the time I fall asleep
どうせなら奪え 奪え
If it's going to be like this, steal it, steal it
害ならした嘘甘いで 逃げ出したい飛び出したい止めてそろそろ死にたいだから
Drenched in harmful sweet lies, wanting to run, jump out, stop me, I want to die soon, therefore...
自分を見ていた
I was looking at myself.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
これは高性能…これは高性能の、本当ですか？
Is this really high-performance?
あ、よかった！嬉しい！
Oh, I'm so glad! I'm so happy!
スタッフも超高性能！
The staff are super high-performance too!
スタッフさんもね、いっぱいカメラね、映してくれてありがとう！
Thank you staff-san for filming me so much with the cameras!
最高としか言えない、本当！
I can only say it's the best, really!
いや、めっちゃ嬉しい！
Man, I'm so happy!
七角！七角、はい、高性能！
Nanaku! Nanaku, yes, high-performance!
むちゃむちゃ嬉しい！ありがとう！
I'm super duper happy! Thank you!
最高、すごい、あ、でも戻ったら戻っちゃった。
The highest, amazing—ah, but when I looked back, it went back.
称号をね、少しずつ戻していきたいなと思います。うん。
I'd like to restore my titles little by little. Yeah.
高性能なんだよ、認めてくれました？
I am high-performance, did you acknowledge it?
認めてくれました？おい！
Did you acknowledge it? Hey!
これローグさっきね、フロウライブの方でリハーサルする時にね、控え室にいたんだけどね、
Roboco, earlier when I was rehearsing for Flow Live in the dressing room...
これマジで怖いことがあって、もうロボ子のTwitter見てネタバレ見ちゃった人分かるんだけど、
There was something seriously scary. Those who saw Roboco's Twitter and saw the spoilers will know,
知ってるみんな！部屋にね、怖いものがあるの！
Everyone knows! There is something scary in the room!
ひやあ！一体みんなロボ子は控え室で見ちゃはいけない、見ちゃったもの…
Yikes! What on earth—Roboco shouldn't have looked in the dressing room, the thing I saw...
一体なんだろうなと思ってたんだけど、いやロボ子びっくりしたよ！部屋に入ったらさ…
I wondered what on earth it was. Man, Roboco was so surprised! When I entered the room...
あ、1個だけおかしがある！見てみようと思って見たらさ、もうびっくり！野号のマカロンがあるんだもん。
Ah, there's one sweet! When I went to check it out, I was so surprised! There were Yagou macarons there.
どうした？顔色悪いしちっちゃくだったぞって思ってしまってね、いや気…いやめっちゃ怖かった！
What's wrong? I thought he looked pale and small, man... it was super scary!
そう、有超さんの人にね、こう、あ、これどうぞって言われたんだけど、え、みたいな。え、これえってなっちゃったロボ子。
Yeah, someone from Yagou's side told me, "Ah, here you go," and I was like, "Eh?" Roboco was like, "Eh, what is this?"
でなんかどうやらね、極生の方が入ってくれたらしいんだけどね、極生の誰かは分からないけど…
And apparently, someone from Gokusei sent it, though I don't know who in Gokusei...
いやすげえのを持ってきたなって、めちゃめちゃ思ってしまったよロボ子。
Man, Roboco couldn't help thinking they brought something amazing.
そう、あれコーラじゃないんだよ、そう、あれね、野号のプリントマカロンなのかな、多分。
Yeah, that wasn't cola. Yeah, that's probably Yagou's printed macarons.
そう、送られてきたらしい。でも、でも全部多分野号だったのね。
Yeah, apparently they were sent. But, but probably all of them were Yagou.
で、もう一個しかなかったのよ。それつまり誰かが野号を食べたんですね。いや、面白い話だな。
And there was only one left. That means someone ate Yagou. Man, what a funny story.
誰だ社長を食べたの？誰だ社長を食べたの？
Who ate the president? Who ate the president?
スタッフさんかな？誰だろうね？
Was it a staff member? Who could it be?
誰が食べたんだろうね、社長のこと。
Who on earth ate the president?
結構な数あったよ。結構な数社長食われてたね、あれは。うん。
There were quite a lot of them. Quite a lot of presidents were eaten, you know. Yeah.
いや、面白かったな。ロボ子もね、後でね、うん、食べようかなと思うんだけど、すごい悩んじゃうよ、あれ。
Man, that was funny. I thought about eating one later too, but it makes you worry so much.
手始めやめてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for stopping!
そう、ぜひともね気になる方はプリントでぜひおしをね食べたいっていう方は物理的にそういうのでも食べることも可能なのね。
Yeah, for those who are curious, if you want to eat your oshi via prints, it's physically possible to eat them that way too.
ね、バレットでもいいと思うんだよね。ただ社長ってだけがちょっと、ちょっとね、食べづらいていうね。
Right, even Valet would be fine, I think. It's just that the president is a bit... hard to eat.
みんなも社長食べたかったら社長をね、プリントアウトして、自分用にね、自分の、あ、バレンタインチョコレートみたいな感じのテンションでね、食べてみてください。
If you guys wanted to eat the president too, print out the president, and try eating it with the kind of vibe like Valentine's chocolate for yourself.
ポルポルかなってロボ子も持ってたんだけど、やっぱりみんなポルちゃんだと思う。
Roboco thought it might be Polpol, but I think everyone is Pol-chan.
僕もポルちゃんにIPをかけてる。でも誰なのかわかんないんだよ。
I'm putting IP on Pol-chan too. But I don't know who it is.
おしを食べたい、物理的にね。そう、ポルポルな気がするんだよな。
I want to eat my oshi, physically. Yeah, I feel like it's Polpol.
ポルポルポルポルポルポルポルポル、食いたくはないぞ。食いたくはないか？食えないか？そっか。
Pol-pol-pol-pol... I don't want to eat them. Don't you want to eat them? Can't you eat them? I see.
言うてね、もう、もう40分早くない？え、マジでライブって、ライブって早いな。
That being said, isn't it already 40 minutes? Huh, live streams really go by fast.
みんなも結構いろんな方を考えていらっしゃいますね。各々の魂もよく受けられておる。
Everyone's thinking about various people. You've all received your respective souls well.
はい、だけど、もう間もなく40分経とうとしております。
Right, but we're about to hit 40 minutes.
はあ、時々、
Ah, time flies...
ドキドキドキドキ みんな
Thumping, thumping, everyone!
もう え、見たいポーズとかあります？ ちょっと今のうちだよ。
Are there any poses you want to see? You better ask right now!
今のうちだけど ロボ子のアイドル衣装がね
While you still can, Roboco's idol outfit...
なかなか なかなかない 3D全身なんて なかなかないレアなんだけど
Is pretty rare—a full 3D model like this doesn't happen often, you know.
実はライブ中だけど 写真撮影も全然してっていいんですよ
Actually, even though we're live, feel free to take screenshots!
え どんなポーズ見たいですか？
Uh, what kind of poses do you want to see?
背中？ 背中はこうだね
The back? The back looks like this.
どう？せれあらっ、ぱえっ、ぱえっ
How's this? Sere-ara, pa-e, pa-e...
すごいなんか ダサいな
That looks super lame.
こんなこんな屈伸して やるとすごいダサいな うん 背伸びターンしてみて？
Doing squats like this looks so lame. Yeah. Try doing a tiptoe turn?
来る？ 来る？
Coming? Is it coming?
ジャンプ！ わーい！
Jump! Yay!
ジャンプもできる！ いっぱいにあてて下さい。
I can jump too! Please take lots of pictures.
「センチョーデス。センチョーくるってやって」
"Sencho-desu. Sencho, do a spin."
えもう なんか なんかやばい
Um, like, this is getting crazy.
もうセンチョーのイメージもうくねくねしてるイメージしか無い わかんない 覚えてないな
My only image of Sencho is her squirming around. I don't know, I don't remember!
くねくねしてるイメージしかない こうだ こんな感じだった気がする
That's the only image I have of her squirming. Like this, I feel like this was it.
怒られそう ねえ
I'm gonna get yelled at. Right?
そうだな 猫？
Let's see, a cat?
やばいロボ子の中指が 閉じろ！ 閉じろ！
Oh no, Roboco's middle finger! Close it! Close it!
閉じない これがこれが限界
It won't close! This is, this is my limit.
にゃあ！ これが限界なのでござるよ お！物理的に閉じた
Meow! This is my limit, you see. Oh! Physically closed!
どうですか？ これでテレ顔とかどうですか？
How is this? How about a shy face with this?
わーお！
Whoa!
ピースはできる でもこっちだな ふふ、こんな感じですね
Peace signs are fine. But this way. Hehe, something like this.
可愛い。フロモデでどう類になってしまうが。
Cute. Though it ends up being the same category as Fromode...
うわ、なんて星座なんだ！ たまたまやってしまってドキドキだけど きゃーって感じ
Whoa, what a constellation! I happened to do it so my heart's racing, but like, "Kyaa!"
きゃーって感じ わあ！見ちゃだめ
Like "Kyaa!" Woah! Don't look!
1、2、3、2、1
1, 2, 3, 2, 1...
ロボ子から見て好きになっちゃうけどね これ昨日のあくあがやってたやつ
You'd fall in love looking from Roboco's POV. This is what Aqua did yesterday.
こう書いてた そう、あれめっちゃすこだった！月
She wrote it like this. Yeah, I loved that so much! Moon.
ねえ、可愛かったね
Right, it was so cute.
スキップしてみて？ロボ子スキップできるかな？あ、ロボ子スキップ覚えている！
Try skipping? Can Roboco skip? Ah, Roboco remembers how to skip!
スキップ 待って待って待って なんかやだやだやだ やだやだやだやだ あーじゃあこんなもんで
Skip, wait wait wait, no no no, no no no no... Ah, well, let's leave it at that.
こんなもんでいいかな？ も、だめだめだめだめ うん
Is this good? No, no, no, no. Yeah.
てことでみんな、あとね、今撮ったやつは ぜひぜひこちらつぶやいてってくださーい！
So everyone, also, please tweet out whatever pictures you just took!
うーん それでもね、ラストはね え 先にこちら宣伝を挟みたいと思います
Um, but before the very end, uh, I'd like to slip in some promotions first.
え、それではこちらの画像。とん！ うーとん、うーとん、うどん、うどん、うーとん、うどん、うどん、うどん！
Uh, well then, here's the image. Ton! U-ton, u-ton, udon, udon, u-ton, udon, udon, udon!
はいというわけで、宣伝を挟まさせていただきます。
Alright then, let me slip in a promotion here.
実はもうみなさんは分かっている通り、アザミナのロボ子のオリジナルソング、三嶋先生が書いてくれた曲、
Actually, as you all already know, "Azamina," Roboco's original song composed by Minoshima-sensei,
そしてAちゃんが書いてくれた歌詞を合わせてロボ子がボーカルを担当いたしました！
and with lyrics written by A-chan, Roboco took charge of the vocals!
私のオリジナルソングアザミナがリリース中なのでぜひともねみなさんチェックしてみてください！
My original song "Azamina" is currently released, so everyone please check it out!
というわけでなんでこっちを宣伝したかというと
So why did I promote this just now?
歌ってもいいですか？ 歌ってもいいですか？
Can I sing a bit? Can I sing?
こないだねAちゃんと一緒に出たの今日はね一人なんだけど歌っていいですか？
The other day I was with A-chan, today I'm by myself, but can I sing?
それじゃあロボ子のオリジナルソング聞いてください。 アザミナ。
Well then, please listen to Roboco's original song. "Azamina."
ひらり ふらり 徘徊ってく 白い夢はもうやめた
Fluttering, drifting, wandering, I've already given up on white dreams.
私ずっと知ってたの 匂いに誘われて墜ちていく
I've known all along, lured by the scent, falling down.
ひらり ふらり さまよってく
Wandering around, fluttering and drifting,
白い夢は もうやめた
I've already given up on white dreams.
わたしずっとしてたのに 上手に誘われて落ちてく
Even though I'd been dreaming them all along, I was skillfully seduced and fell.
与えられた役目を 尋ねることが怖くて
I'm too scared to ask about the role assigned to me,
流れる日々の答えに 濁したのは悪心だけ
and the only thing I muddied in the answers of daily life was pure malice.
さだめられた箱の中 弾けのない寂しさが
Inside the ordained box, an un-bursting loneliness
少し逢うしうしてたの ただよっても知らぬまま
briefly brushed past me, drifting away without even knowing.
切ないが隠した はずだったあの日の台詞
The words I tried so hard to hide that painful day,
分かってる 奥に潜むその目で 見出まぎれもない衝動と
I understand them, hidden deep within those eyes—an undeniable impulse,
ひらり ふらり 飛んでゆける 迷い纏い閉じ込めた
fluttering and drifting as I take flight, trapping the tangled hesitation.
あなたはもう離さないで やがて嘘と知っても
Don't let go of me anymore, even if I soon realize it's a lie.
ひらり ふらり さまよってく
Fluttering and drifting away,
白い夢は もうやめた
I've already given up on white dreams,
わたしずっとしてたのに 上手に誘われて落ちてく
even though I'd been dreaming them all along, I was skillfully seduced and fell.
まとわりつく言葉だけ 何の意味もないくせに
Clinging words that carry no meaning whatsoever,
背負ってる重さに つぶれそうぜのがいてた
under the crushing weight I was carrying, I was crying out to escape.
気づかない国にしていたから こうしてすべてを
Because I was in a land where I didn't notice, I lost everything like this.
ささやいた輪なに染まる覚悟と あのさの代償それだけ
The resolve to be dyed in the whispered ring and that price—that's all.
ひらり ふらり 舞い降りてく 迷い纏い消し去って
Fluttering and drifting down, dancing and erasing the tangled hesitation,
あなたはもう離さないで やがて嘘と知っても
Don't let go of me anymore, even if I soon realize it's a lie.
ひらり ふらり 起こされてく 白い夢は もうやめた
Fluttering and drifting, being awakened, I've already given up on white dreams,
私きっと戻らないに上手に誘われて落ちてく
surely I won't return as I'm skillfully seduced and fall.
ひらり ふらり 飛んでゆける 迷い纏い閉じ込めた
Fluttering and drifting as I take flight, trapping the tangled hesitation.
あなたはもう離さないで やがて嘘と知っても
Don't let go of me anymore, even if I soon realize it's a lie.
ひらり ふらり さまよってく 白い夢は もうやめた
Fluttering and drifting away, I've already given up on white dreams,
わたしずっとしてたのに 上手に誘われて落ちてく
even though I'd been dreaming them all along, I was skillfully seduced and fell.
はい というわけで アザミナでございましたー！
Yes! So that was "Azamina"!
なんかね 最近やっと スーッて歌えるようになってきた
You know, lately I've finally been able to sing smoothly.
多分めちゃめちゃ歌い慣れてきたんだなって 最近ね感じるんだけど
I feel like I've finally gotten really used to singing it lately.
アザミナ混ぜていただきます
Let me mix in some "Azamina".
はい ありがとうございます
Yes, thank you very much!
いや めちゃめちゃね 美味しかっ... 美味しかったじゃなくて
Man, it was super de-... not delicious, wait!
違う違う めちゃめちゃね すごくね 好きなんだよねアザミナは
No, no! I just really, really love "Azamina".
そう ありがとうございます
Yeah, thank you very much!
歌い方独特? 本当? 嬉しいな
My singing style is unique? Really? I'm so happy!
ピーエン ピーエン ピーエン ピーエン
Pien pien pien pien!
つつなくてのいてるときは
When you're feeling down and out,
やさしく抱きしめ慰めて
Hold me gently and comfort me...
ああ それだけ
Ah, just that...
てたてて
Tetatete...
P.M. P.M. P.M. P.M.
あれ 合ってた？
Huh? Was that right?
Was that right?
少し分かんなかったけど、なんかこんな感じだと思って歌っちゃった
A little... No, I didn't know, but I just sang it thinking it felt like this.
言ってみるもんんだね、うん。
Well, it's worth a try, yeah.
P.M. なんかヤギみたいになっちゃうよ
P.M. It ended up sounding like a goat.
これは羊？
Is this a sheep?
いや綿あめより羊の声に似てるかもしれない
No, maybe it sounds more like a sheep than cotton candy.
うん、ちょっと今自信ついてるわ
Yeah, I'm feeling a bit confident now.
ヤギか羊どっちかすっごい似てる気がするロボコ
Roboco sounds a lot like either a goat or a sheep.
あれ？あれ綿あめよりうまいかもしんない
Huh? Maybe it's better than cotton candy.
バレふりか、バレふりはふりふり、ふり！だよ
Balefuri, balefuri is furifuri, furi!
振動すごいね！コロモの振動
The vibration is amazing, Koromo's vibration.
感激まいり！ロボコラって感激できる！ふん！
A grand pilgrimage! Roboco can do a grand pilgrimage! Ha!
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
感激まいり？
A grand pilgrimage?
あれ？ロボコは高精度？あれ？ロボコは高精度だよ！
Huh? Is Roboco high precision? Huh? Roboco is high precision!
ロボコはポンコツ？あれ？ロボコはコン…コンコツ？
Is Roboco a ditz? Huh? Roboco is clu-... clunky?
あれ？ロボコはこ…回って回って回れ！
Huh? Roboco is clu-... Spin, spin, spin around!
違うよ！感激まいりの命令よ、感激まいり！違うよ！
No way! Give the command for the grand pilgrimage, a grand pilgrimage! No!
いや、もう1回行くよ！感激まいりだよ、感激まいりできるからね！
Yeah, let's go again! It's the grand pilgrimage, you can do it!
ロボコの感激まいり！感激り！がん、がん…ロボコの感激目指せ3、2、1、ドーン！
Roboco's grand pilgrimage! Grand... gan, gan... Aim for Roboco's grand pilgrimage in 3, 2, 1, boom!
うわーーーー！というわけで、どーーん！
Waaah! And with that, boom!
はい、ロボコの感激まいりこちらでございます！決まってるでしょ！
Yes, this is Roboco's grand pilgrimage! Nailed it!
いや何このステージ！こんな綺麗な可愛いステージでさ、ステージ、ステージでさ！
Seriously, what is this stage! On such a pretty, cute stage, stage, stage...
何やっとんのよ！何やらしてんのよ！
What on earth are you doing! What are you making me do!
というわけでね、え、もうあと8分ぐらいだ！思ったより丁度よくて草なんだけどびっくりしちゃった。
And with that, we only have about 8 minutes left! It worked out better than expected, so I was surprised.
あー、というわけでね、今日もね、みんなロボコの3Dアイドルライブに、え、来てくれて誠にありがとうございました！
And with that, thank you all so much for coming to Roboco's 3D Idol Live today!
それでは！というわけで終わってですね、えー、
And so, that brings us to an end...
ラストにね、ふふっ、急に終わりじゃなくてね、ラストにね、えーじつは
Not to suddenly end it, but actually, for the very last part...
歌いたい曲がありまして、そちらの方をね、最後に歌って今度は終わりにしていこうかなと思います。
There's a song I want to sing, so I thought I'd sing that at the end before wrapping up.
そう、こちら、アイドルライブでございます、何を間違えようかね、うん。
Right, this is an idol live, what could possibly go wrong, right.
終わるんですけど、最後にね、1曲だけ、あともう1曲聞いて、あともう1曲！このライブの曲やっぱ歌いたいじゃん！そう。
We're wrapping up, but just for the finale, one more song, listen to just one more song! I really want to sing this live song, right.
やっぱりロボコはね、ロボコを歌わせていただいたこともあってますね、やっぱ最後にはこちらの曲を歌って終わりにしたいと思います。それでは最後にね、
After all, since I've had the chance to sing as Roboco, I want to finish by singing this song. So for the very last part...
ねぇねぇちゃん、聞いて！聞いて！ねぇねぇちゃん、聞いて！
Hey-hey-chan, listen! Listen! Hey-hey-chan, listen!
よろしい！じゃあ最後にわ、こちらのほう来て、お疲れ様にしましょう！
All right! Then finally, come over this way and let's call it a day!
キラメキライダー！
Kirameki Rider!
生まれたての時を刻んでいこう
Let's keep marking time with fresh new moments,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times and the best friends,
キラメキになって
Turning into a brilliant sparkle!
イェーイ！最後はこの曲で締めたいと思います！みんなコールセットね！
Yeah! I'd like to close with this song! Everyone get your call sets ready!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
覚えてるかな 最初の歌
I wonder if you remember my very first song.
ボクの声は 震えていた
Back then, my voice was trembling.
あの日から続く 未来は
The future that has continued from that day,
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
Is today, which I seized together with all of you.
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our brand-new heartbeats echo through the stage,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と キラメキに乗って☆ (イェーイ)
with the best times and best friends! (Yay!)
覚えてるかな? 最初の大切な歌 (なつかしいね)
Do you remember our very first precious song?
私 声が震えていた (ほんの少し)
My voice was trembling just a little bit.
あの日から続く未来は
The future that started on that day...
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today, which we seized together!
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート
Getting faster and faster, a speeding heart!
(いっしょに) 行くよ どこまでも
Let's go together, wherever it may be!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK?
Are you ready? Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ！！ 夢のトビラを (1 2 3) (キラメキラライダー☆)
Open wide! The door of our dreams! (1, 2, 3) (Kirameki Rider!)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our brand-new heartbeats echo through the stage,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here because you found us!
きみに会いたくて やってきたんだ
I wanted to meet you, so I came here!
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's all sing together in a never-ending melody!
届いているかな? 私の声 (はっきりりと)
I wonder if my voice reaches you clearly.
届けたいのは きみに笑顔 (そのスマイル！)
I want to deliver my smile to you!
理想の遠さに悔しくて
Even when ideals feel so far away,
みんなと泣き笑ったね
we cried and laughed together.
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 全て抱きしめて
Hold it all close, tighter, tighter, tighter!
(いっしょに) 行こう どこまでも
Let's go together, wherever it may be!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK！？
Are you ready? Is your preparation OK?
すすめ！！ 希望の道を (1 2 3) (キラメキラライダー☆)
Keep pushing forward on the path of hope! (1, 2, 3) (Kirameki Rider!)
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいんだ
Let's play our favorite feelings in full color!
最高の場所 最高の仲間と
With the best place and best friends,
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
we're right here—this is no illusion!
きみのこころが 幸せに染まるように
So that your heart is filled with happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
we layer our harmonies together!
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing and keep dancing!
そんな願いやワガママもいいでしょ?
Is this kind of selfish wish okay?
だって楽しすぎて！ もう止まらない！！
Because it's just too fun, we can't stop anymore!
輝くステージで もっともっと！！ (お願い) ずっと！！
On this shining stage, evermore!
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Words cannot express how happy and loved we feel!
今も 今も 悩みはあるけど
Even though troubles still come and go,
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
we are here, we are right here!
きと同じ世界を見つめて
Looking at the exact same world as you!
(いくよ！) (キラメキラライダー☆)
Let's go! (Kirameki Rider!)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our brand-new heartbeats echo through the stage,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here because you found us!
きみに会いたくて やってきたんだ
I wanted to meet you, so I came here!
みんなで歌おう (せーの) 終わらないメロディ
Let's all sing together in a never-ending melody!
キラメキラライダー☆
(Kirameki Rider!)
(イェーイ)
(Yay!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
Just being happy and having fun isn't enough,
今も 今も 悩みはあるけど
even though we still have our worries today.
ここにいるよ 僕もここにいるよ
We are here, I am right here too!
きみと同じ世界を
Gazing into the very same world as you,
見つめて沈めて
diving deep inside!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let our brand-new heartbeats echo through the stage,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here because you found us!
きみに会いたくて やってきたんだ
I wanted to meet you, so I came here!
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's all sing together in a never-ending melody!
キラメキラライダー☆
(Kirameki Rider!)
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best times and best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
We're right here because you found us!
きみに会いたくて やってきたんだ
I wanted to meet you, so I came here!
みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
Let's all sing together in a never-ending melody!
キラメキラライダー☆
Kirameki Rider!